(this["webpackJsonpjavascript-algorithms"]=this["webpackJsonpjavascript-algorithms"]||[]).push([[0],{22:function(e,t,n){e.exports=n(227)},220:function(e,t,n){},224:function(e,t,n){},226:function(e,t,n){},227:function(e,t,n){"use strict";n.r(t);var a=n(0),r=n.n(a),i=n(18),l=n.n(i),o=(n(27),n(1)),s=n(2),u=n(12),c=n(13);n(28);var h=function(){return r.a.createElement("div",{className:"sidebar"},r.a.createElement("a",{href:"/",className:"logo"},"Topics"),r.a.createElement("nav",null,r.a.createElement("ul",{className:"list"},r.a.createElement("li",{className:"item"},r.a.createElement("header",{className:"title"},r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#bit"},"Bit Manipulation"))),r.a.createElement("li",{className:"item"},r.a.createElement("header",{className:"title"},r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#number"},"Number"))),r.a.createElement("li",{className:"item"},r.a.createElement("header",{className:"title"},"String Manipulation"),r.a.createElement("ul",{className:"subList"},r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#define-anagrams"},"Define anagrams")),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#making-anagrams"},"Making anagrams")))),r.a.createElement("li",{className:"item"},r.a.createElement("header",{className:"title"},r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#array"},"Array"))),r.a.createElement("li",{className:"item"},r.a.createElement("header",{className:"title"},r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#hash"},"Hash"))),r.a.createElement("li",{className:"item"},r.a.createElement("header",{className:"title"},"Sorting"),r.a.createElement("ul",{className:"subList"},r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#bubble-sort"},"Bubble sort")),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#selection-sort"},"Selection sort")),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#insertion-sort"},"Insertion sort")),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#merge-sort"},"Merge sort")),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#quick-sort"},"Quick sort")))),r.a.createElement("li",{className:"item"},r.a.createElement("header",{className:"title"},"Search"),r.a.createElement("ul",{className:"subList"},r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#is-find-index"},"Linear search")),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#binary-search"},"Binary search")),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#search-balanced-sum"},"Balanced Sum")),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#search-two-sum"},"Two Sum")))),r.a.createElement("li",{className:"item"},r.a.createElement("header",{className:"title"},"Linked Lists"),r.a.createElement("ul",{className:"subList"},r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#singly-linked-list"},"Singly-linked List")))),r.a.createElement("li",{className:"item"},r.a.createElement("header",{className:"title"},r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#stack"},"Stack")),r.a.createElement("ul",{className:"subList"},r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#stack-use-array"},"Stack use Array")),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#stack-use-linked-list"},"Stack use Linked List")),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#stack-using-string"},"Stack use Strings")))),r.a.createElement("li",{className:"item"},r.a.createElement("header",{className:"title"},r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#queue"},"Queue")),r.a.createElement("ul",{className:"subList"},r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#queue-use-array"},"Queue via Array")),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#queue-use-linked-lost"},"Queue via Linked list")))),r.a.createElement("li",{className:"item"},r.a.createElement("header",{className:"title"},r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#binary-search-tree"},"Tree")),r.a.createElement("ul",{className:"subList"},r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#binary-search-tree-operations"},"Binary Search Tree")))),r.a.createElement("li",{className:"item"},r.a.createElement("header",{className:"title"},"Graph"),r.a.createElement("ul",{className:"subList"},r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("header",{className:"title"},r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#graph-dfs-flood-fill"},"Flood fill"))))),r.a.createElement("li",{className:"item"},r.a.createElement("header",{className:"title"},r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#recursion"},"Recursion"))),r.a.createElement("li",{className:"item"},r.a.createElement("header",{className:"title"},r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#greedy"},"Greedy Algorithms"))),r.a.createElement("li",{className:"item"},r.a.createElement("header",{className:"title"},r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#dp"},"DP"))),r.a.createElement("li",{className:"item"},r.a.createElement("header",{className:"title"},"Tasks from Eloquent JavaScript"),r.a.createElement("ul",{className:"subList"},r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#eloquent-looping-triangle"},"Looping a triangle")),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#eloquent-fizz-buzz"},"Fizz buzz")),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#eloquent-chessboard"},"Chessboard")),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("a",{href:"#eloquent-is-even"},"Recursion")))))))},m=n(230),f=n(228),d=n(229);function g(e){var t=e.id,n=e.question,a=e.solution,i=e.complexity,l=e.time,o=e.omega,s=e.space,u=e.code,c=e.secondCode,h=e.thirdSolution;return r.a.createElement("details",{className:"details",id:t,"aria-expanded":"false"},r.a.createElement("summary",{role:"button","aria-controls":"content"},r.a.createElement("span",{className:"question"},"Question:\xa0",r.a.createElement("strong",null,n))),r.a.createElement("div",{"aria-hidden":"true"},r.a.createElement("h3",{className:"title"},"Solution:"),r.a.createElement("p",{className:"solutionDesc"},a),r.a.createElement("div",{className:"complexity"},i&&r.a.createElement("div",{className:"complexityDesc"},i),l&&r.a.createElement("p",{className:"runtime"},"Time is ",l),o&&r.a.createElement("p",{className:"runtime"},"Best time is ",o),s&&r.a.createElement("p",null,"Space is ",s)),u&&r.a.createElement(m.a,{language:"javascript",style:f.a},u),c&&r.a.createElement(m.a,{language:"javascript",style:d.a},c),h&&r.a.createElement(m.a,{language:"javascript",style:f.a},h)))}var v=n(4),p=function(e){if(1===e)return 0;if(0===e)return 1;for(var t=1,n=e;n;)e^=t,t<<=1,n>>=1;return e};function E(e){if(0===e)return 1;if(1===e)return 0;for(var t,n=[],a="";e>0;)t=Math.floor(e%2),n.push(t),e=Math.floor(e/2);for(;n.length;)a+=n.pop().toString();for(var r="",i=0;i<a.length;i++)0===Number(a[i])?r+="1":r+="0";return parseInt(r,2)}var y=function(e){if(e<0)return!1;e=e.toString(2);for(var t=0,n=0;n<e.length;n++)1===Number(e[n])&&t++;return 1===t},b=function(e){if(e<=0)return!1;for(;e%2===0;)e/=2;return 1===e},k=function(e){return e>0&&0===(e&e-1)};function S(e,t){return 0!==(e&1<<t)}function w(e,t){return e|1<<t}function O(e,t){return e&~(1<<t)}function N(){return r.a.createElement("div",{className:"bit"},r.a.createElement("h2",{id:"bit"},"Bit Manipulation"),r.a.createElement("ul",null,r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("a",{href:"https://github.com/julia-dizhak/javascript-algorithms/blob/master/README.md#bitwise-operators"},"List of problems with solutions")),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"common-bit-tasks",question:"Common bit tasks",solution:"Tasks: getBit(n,i), setBit(n,i), clearBit(n,i)",time:"",space:"",code:S.toString(),secondCode:w.toString(),thirdSolution:O.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"number-complement",question:"Complement of Base 10 Integer",solution:"The complement strategy is to flip the bits of its binary representation",time:"O(1)",space:"O(1)",code:p.toString(),secondCode:E.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"bit-power-of-two",question:"Power of two: Given an integer, write a function to determine if it is a power of two",solution:"approach iterative, bit manipulation, math and use toString",complexity:"for bit manipulation approach, time and space is O(1)",time:"O(log n)",space:"is O(1)",code:b.toString(),secondCode:k.toString(),thirdSolution:y.toString()}))))}function x(e,t){void 0===t&&(t=2);for(var n=1,a=0;a<t;a++)n*=e;return n}var q=function(e,t){return[e+=t-=e,t=e-t]},j=function(e,t){var n=e;return[e=t,t=n]},z=function(e,t){for(var n=new Array(t).fill(0),a=0,r=0;e>0;){r===t&&(a++,r=0);var i=a*t+(r+1);if(e<i){n[r]+=e;break}n[r]+=i,e-=i,r++}return n};function M(){return r.a.createElement("div",{className:"number"},r.a.createElement("h2",null,"Numbers / Math"),r.a.createElement(g,{id:"number-test",question:"test",code:z.toString()}),r.a.createElement("ul",{id:"number"},r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"number-power",question:"Write a power function",code:x.toString()}),r.a.createElement(g,{id:"number-swap",question:"Swap: 2 variables",time:"O(1)",code:q.toString(),secondCode:j.toString()}))))}console.log("distributeCandies",function(e,t){for(var n=new Array(t).fill(0),a=n.length,r=0;r<a;r++){if(!(e>=0&&e>=r+1)){n[r]=e;break}n[r]=r+1,e-=r+1}for(var i=0;e>0;){if(i>=a&&(i=0),!(e>=n[i]+a+1)){n[i]=n[i]+e;break}n[i]=n[i]+a+1,e-=i+(a+1),i++}return n}(28,3));var C=function(e){for(var t=0;t<e.length/2;t++){var n=e[t];e[t]=e[e.length-t-1],e[e.length-t-1]=n}};function A(e,t,n){if(!(t>=n)){var a=e[t];e[t]=e[n],e[n]=a,A(e,t+1,n-1)}}var B=function(e){A(e,0,e.length-1)},T=function(e){if(1===e.length)return e;for(var t=0,n=e.length-1;t<n;){var a=e[t];e[t]=e[n],e[n]=a,t++,n--}};function L(e,t){if("string"!==typeof e||"string"!==typeof t)throw new Error("defineAnagrams requires two strings to be passed");if(""===e||""===t)return"empty strings";var n=e.length,a=t.length,r={};if(n!==a)return!1;if(n===a){for(var i=e.replace(/[^A-Za-z]+/g,"").toLowerCase(),l=t.replace(/[^A-Za-z]+/g,"").toLowerCase(),o=0;o<n;o++){var s=i.charCodeAt(o)-97;r[s]=(r[s]||0)+1}for(var u=0;u<a;u++){var c=l.charCodeAt(u)-97;if(!r[c])return!1;r[c]--}return Object.values(r).every((function(e){return 0===e}))}}function D(e,t){for(var n=e.length,a=t.length,r={},i={},l=0;l<n;l++)r[e[l]]=r[e[l]]?r[e[l]]+1:1;for(var o=0;o<a;o++)i[t[o]]=i[t[o]]?i[t[o]]+1:1;for(var s=0;s<n;s++)i.hasOwnProperty(e[s])&&(i[e[s]]--,0===i[e[s]]&&delete i[e[s]]);for(var u=0;u<a;u++)r.hasOwnProperty(t[u])&&(r[t[u]]--,0===r[t[u]]&&delete r[t[u]]);var c=Object.values(r),h=Object.values(i);return(c.length>0&&c.reduce((function(e,t){return e+t}))||0)+(h.length>0&&h.reduce((function(e,t){return e+t}))||0)}function W(e){for(var t=e.split(""),n=t.length-1,a=0,r=0;r<n;r++)t[r]===t[r+1]&&a++;return a}var I=n(5),F=function(e,t){return e.filter((function(e){return e===t})).length};function Q(e){for(var t=e.split(""),n=t.length,a={},r=0;r<n;r++){var i=t[r];a[i]=(a[i]||0)+1}var l=Object.values(a),o=Math.max.apply(Math,Object(I.a)(l)),s=Math.min.apply(Math,Object(I.a)(l)),u=F(l,o),c=F(l,s),h=!1;return(o===s||o-s===1&&1===u||1===s&&1===c&&2===Object(I.a)(new Set(l)).length)&&(h=!0),!0===h?"Yes":"No"}var H=function(e,t){for(var n=0,a=0;a<t.length;a++)for(var r=0;r<e.length;r++)if(e.charAt(r)===t.charAt(a)){n++;break}return n},R=function(e,t){var n=0;0===(t.length||e.length)&&(n=0);for(var a=e.split(""),r=t.split(""),i={},l=0;l<t.length;l++){var o=r[l];i[o]=i[o]?i[o]+1:1}for(var s=0;s<e.length;s++){var u=a[s];i[u]&&(n+=i[u])}return n},P=function(e){var t,n={},a=Object(v.a)(e);try{for(a.s();!(t=a.n()).done;){var r=t.value;n[r]=(n[r]||0)+1}}catch(l){a.e(l)}finally{a.f()}for(var i=0;i<e.length;i++){if(1===n[e[i]])return i}return-1},G=function(e,t){for(var n in e)if(e[n]&&e[n]!==t[n])return!1;for(var a in t)if(t[a]&&t[a]!==e[a])return!1;return!0},J=function(e,t){var n=[];if(null==t||null==e||0===e.length||t.length>e.length)return n;for(var a={},r={},i=0;i<t.length;i++)a[t[i]]=(a[t[i]]||0)+1,r[e[i]]=(r[e[i]]||0)+1;for(var l=0,o=t.length;o<=e.length;)G(a,r)&&n.push(l),r[e.charAt(o)]=(r[e.charAt(o)]||0)+1,o++,r[e.charAt(l)]--,l++;return n};console.log("getPermutation",function(e,t){var n=new Array(e+1),a=[],r=1;n[0]=1;for(var i=1;i<=e;i++)r*=i,n[i]=r;for(var l=1;l<=e;l++)a.push(l);t--;for(var o="",s=1;s<=e;s++){var u=Math.floor(t/n[e-s]);o+=a[u],u>-1&&a.splice(u,1),t-=u*n[e-s]}return o}(4,9));!function(e){var t=e.length;if(2===t)return!0;for(var n=e[0][0],a=e[0][1],r=e[1][0],i=(e[1][1]-a)/(r-n),l=2;l<t;l++){if((e[l][1]-a)/(e[l][0]-n)!==i)return!1}}([[1,2],[2,3]]);function U(){return r.a.createElement("div",{className:"sorting"},r.a.createElement("h2",null,"String Manipulation"),r.a.createElement("ul",null,r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"test1",question:"test case"})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"reverse-a-string",question:"Write a function that reverses a string: approach swap, recursion, two pointers",time:"Time is O(n) for all approaches",space:"two pointers space is O(1), recursion is O(n)",code:C.toString(),secondCode:T.toString(),thirdSolution:B.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("details",{className:"details",id:"define-anagrams","aria-expanded":"false","aria-labelledby":"label"},r.a.createElement("summary",{role:"button","aria-controls":"content"},r.a.createElement("span",{className:"question"},"Question:\xa0",r.a.createElement("strong",null,"define anagrams"))),r.a.createElement("div",{"aria-hidden":"true"},r.a.createElement("h3",{className:"title"},"Solution:"),r.a.createElement("p",null,"Anagrams are 2 words meaning anagrams with the same characters but in different order (same exact characters but order doesn\u2019t matter)."),r.a.createElement("ul",{className:"unorderedList"},r.a.createElement("li",null,"Define hash"),r.a.createElement("li",null,"Increase the count for the first string."),r.a.createElement("li",null,"Decrease the count for the second string. If a letter in string 2 is not found in the hash then return false."),r.a.createElement("li",null,"else return true")),r.a.createElement(m.a,{language:"javascript",style:d.a},L.toString())))),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("details",{className:"details",id:"making-anagrams","aria-expanded":"false","aria-labelledby":"label"},r.a.createElement("summary",{role:"button","aria-controls":"content"},r.a.createElement("span",{className:"question"},"Question:\xa0",r.a.createElement("strong",null,"making anagrams"))),r.a.createElement("div",{"aria-hidden":"true"},r.a.createElement("h3",{className:"title"},"Solution:"),r.a.createElement("p",null,"Given two strings, a and b, that may or may not be of the same length, determine the minimum number of character deletions required to make a and b anagrams. Any characters can be deleted from either of the strings."),r.a.createElement(m.a,{language:"javascript",style:f.a},D.toString())))),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("details",{className:"details",id:"string-manipulation-tasks","aria-expanded":"false","aria-labelledby":"label"},r.a.createElement("summary",{role:"button","aria-controls":"content"},"Different tasks related to String Manipulation"),r.a.createElement(g,{id:"alternating-characters",question:"Alternating characters",solution:"\n                  Given two strings, a and b, that may or may not be of the same length,\n                  determine the minimum number of character deletions required to make a and b anagrams.\n                  Any characters can be deleted from either of the strings.\n                ",code:W.toString()}),r.a.createElement(g,{id:"sherlock-valid-string",question:"Sherlock valid string",solution:"\n                  Sherlock considers a string to be valid if all characters of the string\n                  appear the same number of times and one symbol could be deleted.\n                ",code:Q.toString()}),r.a.createElement(g,{id:"numJewelsInStones",question:"Number Jewels in stones",code:R.toString(),secondCode:H.toString()}),r.a.createElement(g,{id:"firstUniqueChar",question:"First Unique Character in a String",complexity:"\n                  The best possible solution here could be of a linear time\n                  because to ensure that the character is unique you have to check the whole string anyway.\n                ",time:"O(n)",space:"O(n)",code:P.toString()}),r.a.createElement(g,{id:"find-all-anagrams",question:"Find all anagrams in a String: approach sliding window and 2 counter Hashes",solution:"\n                  Given a string s and a non-empty string p,\n                  find all the start indices of p's anagrams in s.\n                ",time:"O(N_s + N_p) since it's one pass along both strings",space:"O(1) (or O(n)), because pCount and sCount contain 26 elements each",code:J.toString()})))))}var Y=function(e,t){for(var n=0,a=0,r=[],i=e.length,l=t.length;n<i&&a<l;)e[n]<t[a]?(r.push(e[n]),n++):(r.push(t[a]),a++);return n<i&&(r=[].concat(Object(I.a)(r),Object(I.a)(e.slice(n)))),a<l&&(r=[].concat(Object(I.a)(r),Object(I.a)(t.slice(a)))),r},Z=function(e){var t=e.slice(0);return t},V=function(e){for(var t=[],n=e.length,a=0;a<n;a++)t.push(e[a]);return t},_=function(e){for(var t=new Array(e.length),n=e.length,a=0;a<n;a++)t[a]=e[a];return t};function $(e){for(var t=e.length,n=0,a=0;a<t;a++){var r=e[a+1],i=e[a+2];1===e[a]?a+=1:0===r&&0===i?(n+=2,a+=2):(n+=1,a+=1)}return n}var K=function(e){var t=e.length;if(0===t)return[];if(1===t)return e[0];var n,a={},r=Object(v.a)(e);try{for(r.s();!(n=r.n()).done;){var i=n.value;a[i]=(a[i]||0)+1}}catch(o){r.e(o)}finally{r.f()}for(var l in a)if(a[l]>t/2)return Number(l)},X=function(e){var t,n,a=0,r=Object(v.a)(e);try{for(r.s();!(n=r.n()).done;){var i=n.value;0===a&&(t=i),a+=i===t?1:-1}}catch(l){r.e(l)}finally{r.f()}return t},ee=n(6),te=function(e,t){if(t.length<e-1)return-1;var n,a=Array(e+1).fill(0),r=Object(v.a)(t);try{for(r.s();!(n=r.n()).done;){var i=n.value,l=Object(ee.a)(i,2),o=l[0],s=l[1];a[o]-=1,a[s]+=1}}catch(c){r.e(c)}finally{r.f()}for(var u=1;u<a.length;u++)if(a[u]===e-1)return u;return-1},ne=function(e,t){if(t.length<e-1)return-1;var n,a=Array(e+1).fill(0),r=Array(e+1).fill(0),i=Object(v.a)(t);try{for(i.s();!(n=i.n()).done;){var l=Object(ee.a)(n.value,2),o=l[0],s=l[1];a[o]++,r[s]++}}catch(c){i.e(c)}finally{i.f()}for(var u=1;u<=e;u++)if(0===a[u]&&r[u]===e-1)return u;return-1},ae=function(e){for(var t=e.length,n=-1/0,a=0;a<t;a++)for(var r=a;r<t;r++){for(var i=0,l=a;l<=r;l++)i+=e[l];i>n&&(n=i)}return n},re=function(e){var t=e.length;if(1===t)return e[0];for(var n=-1/0,a=0;a<t;a++)for(var r=0,i=a;i<t;i++)r+=e[i],n=Math.max(n,r);return n},ie=function(e){for(var t=0;t<e.length-1;t+=2)if(e[t]!==e[t+1])return e[t];return e[e.length-1]},le=function(e){for(var t=0,n=e.length-1;t<n;){var a=Math.floor(t+(n-t)/2),r=(n-a)%2===0;if(e[a+1]===e[a])r?t=a+2:n=a-1;else{if(e[a-1]!==e[a])return e[a];r?n=a-2:t=a+1}}return e[t]};function oe(e){for(var t=0,n=e.length-1;t<n;){var a=Math.floor(t+(n-t)/2);a%2===1&&a--,e[a]===e[a+1]?t=a+2:n=a}return e[t]}var se=function(e){for(var t=[],n=1;n<e.length;n++)e[n]!==e[n+1]&&t.push(e[n]);return t.length};function ue(){return r.a.createElement("div",{className:"sorting"},r.a.createElement("h2",null,"Array"),r.a.createElement(g,{id:"test-array"}),r.a.createElement("ul",{id:"array"},r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"remove-duplicates-in-sorted-array",question:"Remove duplicates from sorted array: approach 2 pointers, slow and fast runner",time:"O(n)",space:"O(1)",code:se.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"array-clone",question:"Clone arrays",code:Z.toString(),secondCode:V.toString(),thirdSolution:_.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"array-jump-on-clouds",question:"Jump on clouds",solution:"",code:$.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"merge-two-arrays",question:"merge two sorted arrays (mergeSort algorithm)",solution:"Below is just an implementation of mergeSort algorithm",time:"runtime is O(n log n)",space:"",code:Y.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"sinlgle-element-in-sorted-array",question:"Single element in sorted array: approach brute force, binary search, BS only on even indexes",solution:"for brute force time is O(n), space is O(1)",time:"binary search approach O(log n)",space:"binary search approachO(1)",code:ie.toString(),secondCode:le.toString(),thirdSolution:oe.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"majority-element",question:"Majority elements: using hash, sort, Voting Moore algorithm",solution:"",time:"Moore O(n)",space:"Moore O(1)",code:K.toString(),secondCode:X.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"find-judge",question:"Find judge in the town, approach with one and two arrays",solution:"\n                In a town, there are N people labelled from 1 to N.\n                There is a rumor that one of these people is secretly the town judge.\n                If the town judge exists, then:\n                1 The town judge trusts nobody.\n                2 Everybody (except for the town judge) trusts the town judge.\n                3 There is exactly one person that satisfies properties 1 and 2.\n\n                You are given trust, an array of pairs trust[i] = [a, b] representing that the person labelled a trusts the person labelled b.\n                If the town judge exists and can be identified, return the label of the town judge.\n                Otherwise, return -1.\n              ",complexity:"\n              Recall that N is number of people, and E is the number of edges (trusts relationships)\n              Time complexity is O(E). We need to loop through the E edges in trust,\n              and the argument about relationship between N and E still applies.\n              Space complexity: O(N) - allocating an array of length N\n            ",time:"O(max(N, E) = O(N+E), because is E >= N-1 => O(E) number of trusts relationship",space:"O(N) allocating an array of length N",code:te.toString(),secondCode:ne.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"max-contiguous-subarray-sum",question:"Max contiguous subarray sum: brute force cubic and quadratic time",solution:"\n                test\n              ",complexity:"\n              test\n            ",time:"",space:"",code:ae.toString(),secondCode:re.toString()}))))}var ce=function(){function e(){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.storage=""}return Object(s.a)(e,[{key:"isEmpty",value:function(){return 0===this.storage.length}},{key:"push",value:function(e){this.storage=this.storage.concat("***",e)}},{key:"pop",value:function(){var e=this.storage.lastIndexOf("***"),t=this.storage.slice(e+3);return this.storage=this.storage.substr(0,e),t}},{key:"peek",value:function(){return this.storage[this.storage.length-1]}}]),e}(),he=function(){function e(){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.stack=[]}return Object(s.a)(e,[{key:"isEmpty",value:function(){return 0===this.length}},{key:"push",value:function(e){this.stack.push(e)}},{key:"pop",value:function(){if(this.isEmpty())throw new Error("stack is empty");return this.stack.pop()}},{key:"peek",value:function(){return this.stack[this.stack.length-1]}},{key:"clear",value:function(){return[]}},{key:"print",value:function(){console.log("stack",this.stack.toString())}},{key:"length",get:function(){return this.stack.length}}]),e}(),me=function e(t,n){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.val=t,this.next=null},fe=function(){function e(){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.head=null,this.length=0}return Object(s.a)(e,[{key:"isEmpty",value:function(){return 0===this.length}},{key:"push",value:function(e){var t=new me(e,null);this.head?(t.next=this.head,this.head=t):this.head=t,this.length++}},{key:"pop",value:function(){return this.head?(this.head=this.head.next,this.length--,this.head.val):null}},{key:"peek",value:function(){return this.head?this.head.val:null}},{key:"clear",value:function(){this.head=null,this.length=0}}]),e}(),de=new fe;function ge(e){this.capacity=e||1/0,this.storage={},this.count=0}de.push(1),de.push(2),de.pop(),ge.prototype.push=function(e){return this.count<this.capacity?(this.storage[this.count++]=e,this.count):"Max capacity already reached. Remove element before adding a new one."},ge.prototype.pop=function(){if(0===this.count)return"No element inside the stack. Add element before popping.";var e=this.storage[this.count--];return delete this.storage[this.count],this.count<0&&(this.count=0),e},ge.prototype.count=function(){return this.count};var ve=new ge;ve.push("a"),ve.push("b"),ve.push("c");var pe=function(){function e(){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.stack=[],this.minStack=[]}return Object(s.a)(e,[{key:"push",value:function(e){this.stack.push(e),(0===this.minStack.length||e<=this.minStack[this.minStack.length-1])&&this.minStack.push(e)}},{key:"pop",value:function(){this.stack.pop()===this.minStack[this.minStack.length-1]&&this.minStack.pop()}},{key:"top",value:function(){return this.stack[this.stack.length-1]}},{key:"getMin",value:function(){return this.minStack[this.minStack.length-1]}}]),e}(),Ee=function(){function e(){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.elements=[]}return Object(s.a)(e,[{key:"push",value:function(e){this.elements.push({value:e,min:0===this.elements.length?e:Math.min(e,this.getMin())})}},{key:"pop",value:function(){this.elements.pop()}},{key:"top",value:function(){return this.elements[this.elements.length-1].value}},{key:"getMin",value:function(){return this.elements[this.elements.length-1].min}}]),e}(),ye=function(){function e(){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.stack=[],this.maxStack=[]}return Object(s.a)(e,[{key:"push",value:function(e){this.stack.push(e);var t=0===this.maxStack.length?e:this.peekMax();this.maxStack.push(t>e?t:e)}},{key:"pop",value:function(){return this.maxStack.pop(),this.stack.pop()}},{key:"popMax",value:function(){for(var e=[];this.top()!==this.peekMax();)e.unshift(this.stack.pop()),this.maxStack.pop();for(var t=this.pop(),n=0,a=e;n<a.length;n++){var r=a[n];this.push(r)}return t}},{key:"top",value:function(){return this.stack[this.stack.length-1]}},{key:"peekMax",value:function(){return this.maxStack[this.maxStack.length-1]}}]),e}(),be=new ye;function ke(){return r.a.createElement("div",{className:"stack",id:"stack"},r.a.createElement("h2",null,"Stack"),r.a.createElement("ul",null,r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"stack-use-array",question:"Stack via Array",code:he.toString(),time:"every operation takes constant time",space:"less wasted space"})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"stack-use-linked-list",question:"Stack via Linked List",code:fe.toString(),time:"for .push and pop() takes constant time",space:"need space for pointers"})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"stack-using-string",question:"Stack via String",code:ce.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"stack-using-object",question:"Stack via Object",code:ge.toString()}))),r.a.createElement("ul",null,r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("details",{className:"details",id:"stack-different-tasks","aria-expanded":"false","aria-labelledby":"label"},r.a.createElement("summary",{role:"button","aria-controls":"content"},"Different problems related to Stacks"),r.a.createElement(g,{id:"min-stack",question:"Min Stack: approach 2 Stacks, approach minimum pairs",time:"O(1) for all operation",space:"O(n)",code:pe.toString(),secondCode:Ee.toString()}),r.a.createElement(g,{id:"max-stack",question:"Max Stack: approach 2 Stacks",solution:"Design a max stack that supports push, pop, top, peekMax and popMax.",complexity:"\n                  Can we design operations in O(1) like the min stack problem? No\n                  Because if it were, you could use this data structure to sort an array of numbers in O(n) time.\n                  So, at the very least, either push(x) or popMax() must be O(log n)\n                  ",time:"O(N) for the popMax operation, and O(1) for the other operations",space:"O(N), the maximum size of the stack.",code:ye.toString(),secondCode:ye.toString()})))))}be.push(5),be.push(3),be.push(6),be.push(5),be.push(3),be.popMax();var Se=function(){function e(){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.queue=[]}return Object(s.a)(e,[{key:"isEmpty",value:function(){return 0===this.length}},{key:"enqueue",value:function(e){this.queue.push(e)}},{key:"dequeue",value:function(){if(this.isEmpty())throw new Error("queue is empty");return this.queue.shift()}},{key:"peek",value:function(){if(this.isEmpty())throw new Error("queue is empty");return this.queue[0]}},{key:"length",get:function(){return this.queue.length}}]),e}(),we=new Se;we.enqueue(1),we.enqueue(2),we.enqueue(3),we.dequeue();var Oe=function e(t){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.val=t,this.next=null},Ne=function(){function e(){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.head=null,this.length=0}return Object(s.a)(e,[{key:"isEmpty",value:function(){return 0===this.length}},{key:"getHead",value:function(){return this.head.val}},{key:"getLength",value:function(){return this.length}},{key:"enqueue",value:function(e){var t=new Oe(e);if(this.head){for(var n=this.head;n.next;)n=n.next;n.next=t}else this.head=t;this.length++}},{key:"dequeue",value:function(){if(!this.head)return"Queue is empty!";var e=this.head;return this.head=this.head.next,this.length--,e.val}},{key:"peek",value:function(){return this.head?this.head.val:"Queue is empty!"}},{key:"print",value:function(){for(var e=this.head;e;)console.log(e.val),e=e.next}}]),e}(),xe=function(){function e(){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.head=null,this.tail=null,this.length=0}return Object(s.a)(e,[{key:"isEmpty",value:function(){return 0===this.length}},{key:"getHead",value:function(){return this.head.val}},{key:"getLength",value:function(){return this.length}},{key:"enqueue",value:function(e){var t=new Oe(e);this.head?(this.tail.next=t,this.tail=t):(this.head=t,this.tail=t),this.length++}},{key:"dequeue",value:function(){if(!this.head)return"Queue is empty!";var e=this.head;return this.head=this.head.next,this.length--,e.val}},{key:"peek",value:function(){return this.head?this.head.val:"Queue is empty!"}}]),e}(),qe=function(){function e(){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.stackNewest=[],this.stackOldest=[]}return Object(s.a)(e,[{key:"empty",value:function(){return!this.stackNewest.length&&!this.stackOldest.length}},{key:"size",value:function(){return this.stackNewest.length+this.stackOldest.length}},{key:"enqueue",value:function(e){this.stackNewest.push(e)}},{key:"shiftStacks",value:function(){if(!this.stackOldest.length)for(;this.stackNewest.length;)this.stackOldest.push(this.stackNewest.pop())}},{key:"peek",value:function(){return this.shiftStacks(),this.stackOldest[this.stackOldest.length-1]}},{key:"dequeue",value:function(){return this.shiftStacks(),this.stackOldest.pop()}}]),e}();function je(){return r.a.createElement("div",{className:"queue",id:"queue"},r.a.createElement("h2",null,"Queue"),r.a.createElement("ul",null,r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"queue-use-array",question:"Queue via array",code:Se.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"queue-use-linked-list",question:"Queue via linked list (1 pointer and 2 pointers)",code:Ne.toString(),secondCode:xe.toString()}))),r.a.createElement("ul",null,r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("details",{className:"details",id:"queue-problems","aria-expanded":"false","aria-labelledby":"label"},r.a.createElement("summary",{role:"button","aria-controls":"content"},"Different problems related to Queues"),r.a.createElement(g,{id:"queue-use-2-stacks",question:"",time:"",space:"",code:qe.toString()})))))}var ze=function e(t){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.val=t,this.next=null},Me=function(){function e(){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.head=null,this.size=0}return Object(s.a)(e,[{key:"get",value:function(e){if(e<0||e>this.size-1||0===this.size)return-1;if(0===e)return this.head.val;for(var t=0,n=this.head;n;){if(t===e)return n.val;t++,n=n.next}return-1}},{key:"getAt",value:function(e){if(0===e)return this.head;for(var t=0,n=this.head;n;){if(t===e)return n;t++,n=n.next}return null}},{key:"addAtHead",value:function(e){var t=new ze(e);this.head?(t.next=this.head,this.head=t):this.head=t,this.size+=1}},{key:"addAtTail",value:function(e){var t=new ze(e);if(this.head){for(var n=this.head;n.next;)n=n.next;n.next=t}else this.head=t;this.size++}},{key:"addAtIndex",value:function(e,t){var n=new ze(t);if(!(e>this.size)){if(this.head||(this.head=n),0===e)return this.addAtHead(t);if(e===this.size)return this.addAtTail(t);var a=this.getAt(e-1);n.next=a.next,a.next=n,this.size++}}},{key:"deleteAtIndex",value:function(e){if(!(e>=this.size-1||e<0))if(this.size--,0!==e){for(var t=0,n=this.head;t<e-1;)n=n.next,t++;n.next=n.next.next}else this.head=this.head.next}},{key:"deleteList",value:function(){this.head=null}},{key:"printList",value:function(){for(var e=[],t=this.head;t;)e.push(t.val),t=t.next;return e.join(" -> ")}}]),e}();function Ce(){return r.a.createElement("div",{className:"number"},r.a.createElement("h2",null,"Linked Lists"),r.a.createElement("h4",null,"Singly-linked List"),r.a.createElement("ul",null,r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"singly-linked-list",question:"Singly linked list implementation",code:Me.toString()}))))}var Ae=function(){function e(){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.keys=[],this.values=[]}return Object(s.a)(e,[{key:"set",value:function(e,t){this.keys.push(e),this.keys.push(t)}},{key:"get",value:function(e){for(var t=0;t<this.keys.length;t++)if(this.keys[t]===e)return this.values[t]}}]),e}(),Be=function(){function e(){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.data={},this.length=0}return Object(s.a)(e,[{key:"add",value:function(e){this.contains(e)||this.length++,e=e.toString(),this.data[e]=e}},{key:"contains",value:function(e){return e=e.toString(),!!this.data[e]&&this.data.hasOwnProperty(e)}},{key:"remove",value:function(e){this.contains(e)&&(delete this.data[e.toString()],this.length--)}},{key:"size",value:function(){return this.length}},{key:"isEmpty",value:function(){return 0===this.length}},{key:"toArray",value:function(){}}]),e}(),Te=function(){function e(){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.data={},this.length=0}return Object(s.a)(e,[{key:"add",value:function(e){this.data[e]||(this.data[e]=!0,this.length++)}},{key:"remove",value:function(e){this.data[e]&&(delete this.data[e],this.length--)}},{key:"contains",value:function(e){return!!this.data[e]}},{key:"size",value:function(){return this.length}},{key:"isEmpty",value:function(){return 0===this.length}}]),e}(),Le=new Be;function De(e,t){var n=e.length;if(0===n)return[];for(var a=0;a<n;a++)for(var r=a+1;r<n;r++)if(e[r]===t-e[a])return[a,r];return-1}function We(e,t){if(0===e.length)return[];for(var n=new Map,a=0;a<e.length;a++)n.set(e[a],a);for(var r=0;r<e.length;r++){var i=t-e[r];if(n.has(i)&&n.get(i)!==r)return[r,n.get(i)]}return-1}function Ie(e,t){if(0===e.length)return[];for(var n={},a=0;a<e.length;a++){var r=n[t-e[a]];if(void 0!==r)return[r,a];n[e[a]]=a}return-1}Le.add(1),Le.add(2),Le.contains(1),Le.remove(2),Le.remove(3),Le.contains(3),Le.add(1),Le.add(2),console.log("hash",Le);var Fe=function(e){if(null===e||0===e.length)return 0;for(var t=(e=e.sort((function(e,t){return e-t}))).length,n=0;n<t;n++)if(e[n]>=t-n)return t-n;return 0};console.log("hIndexSort",Fe([3,0,6,1,5])),console.log("hIndexSort 1",Fe([0,1,1,1,1,1,2,2,2,2]));var Qe=function(e){for(var t=e.length,n=0,a=new Array(t+1).fill(0),r=0;r<t;r++)e[r]>=t?a[t]++:a[e[r]]++;for(var i=t;i>0;i--)if((n+=a[i])>=i)return i;return console.log("arr",a),0};function He(){return r.a.createElement("div",{className:"hash"},r.a.createElement("h2",null,"Hash / Hash Table"),r.a.createElement("ul",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"test",question:"",code:Qe.toString()}),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"hashMap",question:"HashMap / HashTable implementation: use array",code:Ae.toString(),time:"",space:""})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"hashSet",question:"HashSet implementation: use object",code:Be.toString(),secondCode:Te.toString(),time:"",space:""})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"search-two-sum",question:"Two sum using hash",solution:"\n              Given an array of integers, return indices of the two numbers such that they add up to a specific target.\n              You may assume that each input has exactly one solution.\n              And you may not use the same element twice.\n            ",time:"O(n)",space:"O(n). The extra space required depends on the number of items stored in the hash table, which stores exactly nn elements",code:De.toString(),secondCode:We.toString(),thirdSolution:Ie.toString()}))))}console.log("hIndex",Qe([3,0,6,1,5]));var Re=function e(t,n,a,r){var i=arguments.length>4&&void 0!==arguments[4]?arguments[4]:t[n][a];return n<0||a<0||n>=t.length||a>=t[n].length||t[n][a]!==i||t[n][a]===r||(t[n][a]=r,e(t,n-1,a,r,i),e(t,n+1,a,r,i),e(t,n,a-1,r,i),e(t,n,a+1,r,i)),t},Pe=function(e,t,n,a){var r=e[t][n];return r!==a&&function e(t,n,a,r,i){var l=t.length,o=t[0].length;if(n<0||n>=l||a<0||a>=o||t[n][a]!==r)return;t[n][a]=i,e(t,n-1,a,r,i),e(t,n+1,a,r,i),e(t,n,a-1,r,i),e(t,n,a+1,r,i)}(e,t,n,r,a),e};function Ge(){return r.a.createElement("div",{className:"graph"},r.a.createElement("h2",null,"Graph"),r.a.createElement("ul",{id:"graph"},r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"test",question:"test"})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"graph-dfs-flood-fill",question:"Flood fill image bitmap algorithm using dfs (Depth-First Search)",solution:"We can use a function dfs to perform a flood-fill on a target pixel.",time:"O(N), where N is the number of pixels in the image. We might process every pixel",space:"O(N), the size of the implicit call stack when calling dfs.",code:Re.toString(),secondCode:Pe.toString()}))))}var Je=function e(t,n,a){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.val=void 0===t?0:t,this.left=void 0===n?null:n,this.right=void 0===a?null:a},Ue=function(){function e(t){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.root=new Je(t)}return Object(s.a)(e,[{key:"insert",value:function(e){var t=arguments.length>1&&void 0!==arguments[1]?arguments[1]:this.root,n=new Je(e);null===t&&(t=n);var a=[];for(a.push(t);a.length;){var r=a[0];if(a.shift(),null===r.left){r.left=n;break}if(a.push(r.left),null===r.right){r.right=n;break}a.push(r.right)}}}]),e}(),Ye=function e(t,n,a){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.val=void 0===t?0:t,this.left=void 0===n?null:n,this.right=void 0===a?null:a},Ze=function(){function e(t){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.root=new Ye(t),this.count=1}return Object(s.a)(e,[{key:"size",value:function(){return this.count}},{key:"insert",value:function(e){!function t(n){var a=new Ye(e);if(null===n)n=a;else{if(e===n.val)return console.log("equal val"),null;e<n.val?null===n.left?n.left=a:t(n.left):null===n.right?n.right=a:t(n.right)}}(this.root),this.count++}},{key:"insertNode",value:function(e){for(var t=arguments.length>1&&void 0!==arguments[1]?arguments[1]:this.root,n=new Ye(e),a=t,r=null;null!==a;)r=a,a=e<=a.val?a.left:a.right;null===r?r=n:e<=r.val?r.left=n:r.right=n,this.count++}},{key:"contains",value:function(e){for(var t=this.root;t;){if(e===t.val)return!0;t=e<t.val?t.left:t.right}return!1}},{key:"height",value:function(){var e=arguments.length>0&&void 0!==arguments[0]?arguments[0]:this.root;if(null===e)return-1;if(null===e.left&&null===e.right)return 0;if(null===e.left)return this.height(e.right)+1;if(null===e.right)return this.height(e.left)+1;var t=this.height(e.left),n=this.height(e.right);return Math.max(t,n)+1}},{key:"lowestCommonAncestor",value:function(e,t){var n=arguments.length>2&&void 0!==arguments[2]?arguments[2]:this.root;return n.value>e&&n.value>t?this.lowestCommonAncestor(e,t,n.left):n.value<e&&n.value<t?this.lowestCommonAncestor(e,t,n.right):n}}]),e}(),Ve=new Ze(4);Ve.insert(2),Ve.insert(3),Ve.insert(1),Ve.lowestCommonAncestor(2,7);var _e=function e(t,n,a){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.val=void 0===t?0:t,this.left=void 0===n?null:n,this.right=void 0===a?null:a},$e=function e(t){if(!t)return null;var n=e(t.left),a=e(t.right);return t.left=a,t.right=n,t},Ke=new(function(){function e(t){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.root=null}return Object(s.a)(e,[{key:"add",value:function(e){var t=this.root;if(null===t)this.root=new _e(e);else{!function t(n){if(e<n.val){if(null===n.left)n.left=new _e(e);else if(null!==n.left)return t(n.left)}else{if(!(e>n.val))return null;if(null===n.right)n.right=new _e(e);else if(null!==n.right)return t(n.right)}}(t)}}}]),e}());[4,2,7,1,3,6,9].map((function(e,t){return Ke.add(e),Ke})),Ke=JSON.parse(JSON.stringify(Ke)).root;$e(Ke);var Xe=function(e){var t=[];if(null===e)return t;var n=[];for(null!==e&&n.push(e);n.length;){var a=n.pop();t.push(a.val),a.right&&n.push(a.right),a.left&&n.push(a.left)}return t},et=function e(t,n,a){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.val=void 0===t?0:t,this.left=void 0===n?null:n,this.right=void 0===a?null:a},tt=new et(1);tt.right=new et(2),tt.right.left=new et(3);var nt=function e(t,n,a){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.val=void 0===t?0:t,this.left=void 0===n?null:n,this.right=void 0===a?null:a},at=function(e){var t=[];if(!e)return t;var n=[];for(n.push(e);n.length;){var a=n.shift();t.push(a.val),a.left&&n.push(a.left),a.right&&n.push(a.right)}return t},rt=new nt(0);rt.left=new nt(3),rt.right=new nt(2),rt.left.left=new nt(9),rt.right.right=new nt(10),console.log("tree",rt),console.log("levelOrderForLeetcode",function(e){var t=[];if(!e)return t;var n=[];for(n.push(e);n.length>0;){for(var a=n.length,r=[],i=0;i<a;i++){var l=n.shift();r.push(l.val),l.left&&n.push(l.left),l.right&&n.push(l.right)}t.push(r)}return t}(rt));var it=function e(t,n,a){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.val=void 0===t?0:t,this.left=void 0===n?null:n,this.right=void 0===a?null:a},lt=new it(3);lt.left=new it(9),lt.right=new it(20),lt.right.left=new it(15),lt.right.right=new it(7),console.log("verticalTraversalWithoutOrder",function(e){if(null===e)return[];var t=[];null!==e&&t.push([e,0,0]);for(var n=[];t.length;){var a=t.shift(),r=Object(ee.a)(a,3),i=r[0],l=r[1],o=r[2];i.left&&t.push([i.left,l-1,o-1]),i.right&&t.push([i.right,l+1,o-1]),i&&n.push([i.val,l,o])}for(var s={},u=0;u<n.length;u++){var c=Object(ee.a)(n[u],3),h=c[0],m=c[1];c[2];if(void 0!==s[m]){var f=s[m].push(h);s[m]=f}else s[m]=[h]}return console.log("list",n),console.log("hash",s),n}(lt));var ot=function e(t,n,a){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.val=void 0===t?0:t,this.left=void 0===n?null:n,this.right=void 0===a?null:a},st=function(e,t){if(null===e)return!1;null!==e&&[].push([e,e.val]);return console.log("result2",[]),!1},ut=new ot(5);ut.left=new ot(4),ut.right=new ot(8),ut.left.left=new ot(11),ut.right.left=new ot(13),ut.right.right=new ot(4),ut.left.left.left=new ot(7),ut.left.left.right=new ot(2),ut.right.right.right=new ot(4),console.log("tree",ut),console.log("hasPathSum",st(ut));function ct(e,t,n){this.val=void 0===e?0:e,this.left=void 0===t?null:t,this.right=void 0===n?null:n}var ht=function(e,t){for(var n=new Map,a=0;a<e.length;a++)n.set(e[a],a);return function e(t,a,r,i,l,o){if(a>r||l>o)return null;var s=new ct(i[o]),u=n.get(s.val);return s.left=e(t,a,u-1,i,l,l+u-a-1),s.right=e(t,u+1,r,i,l+u-a,o-1),s}(e,0,e.length-1,t,0,t.length-1)}([2,1,3],[2,3,1]);console.log("build tree",ht);var mt=function e(t,n,a){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.val=void 0===t?0:t,this.left=void 0===n?null:n,this.right=void 0===a?null:a},ft=new(function(){function e(t){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.root=new mt(t)}return Object(s.a)(e,[{key:"getHeight",value:function(){var e=arguments.length>0&&void 0!==arguments[0]?arguments[0]:this.root;if(null===e)return 0;var t=this.getHeight(e.left),n=this.getHeight(e.right);return 1+Math.max(t,n)}},{key:"getWidth",value:function(e,t){return null===e?0:1===t?1:t>1?this.getWidth(e.left,t-1)+this.getWidth(e.right,t-1):0}},{key:"getMaxWidth",value:function(){for(var e=arguments.length>0&&void 0!==arguments[0]?arguments[0]:this.root,t=0,n=0,a=this.getHeight(e),r=0;r<a;r++)(n=this.getWidth(e,r))>t&&(t=n);return t}},{key:"insertNode",value:function(e){var t=arguments.length>1&&void 0!==arguments[1]?arguments[1]:this.root,n=new mt(e);null===t&&(t=n);var a=[];for(a.push(t);a.length;){var r=a[0];if(a.shift(),null===r.left){r.left=n;break}if(a.push(r.left),null===r.right){r.right=n;break}a.push(r.right)}}}]),e}())(1);ft.insertNode(2),ft.insertNode(3),ft.insertNode(4),ft.insertNode(5),ft.insertNode(6),ft.insertNode(7),ft.insertNode(8);var dt=function(e){if(null===e)return 0;var t=0,n=[];for(n.push([e,0]);n.length;){for(var a=n.length,r=void 0,i=void 0,l=void 0,o=0;o<a;o++){var s=n.shift(),u=Object(ee.a)(s,2);r=u[0],i=u[1],0===o&&(l=i),r.left&&n.push([r.left,2*i]),r.right&&n.push([r.right,2*i+1])}var c=i-l+1|0;t=Math.max(t,c)}return t}(ft=JSON.parse(JSON.stringify(ft)).root);function gt(){return r.a.createElement("div",{className:"tree"},r.a.createElement("h2",null,"Trees"),r.a.createElement("ul",{id:"binary-search-tree"},r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"test-bt",question:"",code:st.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"bt-implementation",question:"BT implementation: .insert(node)",solution:"insert(node): iterative + Queue",complexity:"",time:"",space:"",code:Ue.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"binary-search-tree-operations",question:"Binary Search Tree: .insert, .contains, height, lowest common ancestor",solution:"",complexity:"\n                Binary search trees provide logarithmic time for the common operations of lookup, insertion, and deletion in the average case,\n                and linear time in the worst case.\n                Why is this? Each of those basic operations requires us to find an item in the tree\n                and because of the tree structure at each parent node we are branching left or right\n                and effectively excluding half the size of the remaining tree.\n                This makes the search proportional to the logarithm of the number of nodes in the tree,\n                which creates logarithmic time for these operations in the average case.\n              ",time:"O(log(n)) in the average case, linear - in worst cases",space:"",code:Ze.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"bt-levelorder",question:"Level order (bottom level) traversal BT",time:"O(n)",space:"O(n)",code:at.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"bt-preorder-traversal",question:"Preorder traversal BT",time:"",space:"",code:Xe.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"invert-binary-tree",question:"Invert Binary Tree: approach recursion",time:"is O(n), since each node in the tree is visited only once",space:"is O(h) because of recursion, O(h) function calls will be placed on the stack in the worst case, where h is the height of the tree",code:$e.toString()}))))}console.log("width",dt);var vt=function(){function e(){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.values=[]}return Object(s.a)(e,[{key:"bubbleUp",value:function(){for(var e=this.values.length-1;e>0;){var t=Math.floor((e-1)/2);if(!(this.values[t]<this.values[e]))break;this.swap(e,t),e=t}return 0}},{key:"swim",value:function(e){for(;e>1;){var t=Math.floor((e-1)/2);if(!(this.values[t]<this.values[e]))break;this.swap(e,t),e=t}return 0}},{key:"insertOntoEnd",value:function(e){return this.values.push(e),this.bubbleUp(),this.values}},{key:"insert",value:function(e){var t=this.values.length;return this.values.push(e),this.swim(t),this.values}},{key:"bubbleDown",value:function(){for(var e=0,t=this.values.length,n=this.values[0];;){var a=2*e+1,r=2*e+2,i=void 0,l=void 0,o=null;if(a<t&&(i=this.values[a])>n&&(o=a),r<t&&((l=this.values[r])>n&&null===o||l>i&&null!==o)&&(o=r),null===o)break;this.swap(e,o),e=o}}},{key:"deleteMax",value:function(){this.swap(0,this.values.length-1);var e=this.values.pop();return this.values.length>1&&this.bubbleDown(),e}},{key:"max",value:function(){return this.values[0]}},{key:"swap",value:function(e,t){var n=this.values[e];this.values[e]=this.values[t],this.values[t]=n}}]),e}(),pt=new vt;function Et(){return r.a.createElement("div",{className:"heap",id:"heap"},r.a.createElement("h2",null,"Heap"),r.a.createElement(g,{id:"",question:"test"}),r.a.createElement("ul",null,r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"max-binary-heap",question:"Max Binary Heap",code:vt.toString()}))))}pt.insert(100),pt.insert(20),pt.insert(80),pt.insert(30),pt.insert(70),pt.insert(40),pt.deleteMax();var yt=function(){function e(){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.head={key:"",children:{}}}return Object(s.a)(e,[{key:"insert",value:function(e){var t=this.head,n=e.slice(0,1),a=null;for(e=e.slice(1);"undefined"!==typeof t.children[n]&&n.length>0;)t=t.children[n],n=e.slice(0,1),e=e.slice(1);for(;n.length>0;)a={key:n,val:0===e.length?null:void 0,children:{}},t.children[n]=a,t=a,n=e.slice(0,1),e=e.slice(1)}},{key:"search",value:function(e){var t=this.head,n=e.slice(0,1),a=0;for(e=e.slice(1);"undefined"!==typeof t.children[n]&&n.length>0;)t=t.children[n],n=e.slice(0,1),e=e.slice(1),a+=1;return null===t.val&&0===e.length&&(console.log("d",a),!0)}},{key:"remove",value:function(e){}}]),e}(),bt=new yt;bt.insert("bad"),bt.search("bad"),console.log("trie",bt);var kt=function(){this.root={}};kt.prototype.insert=function(e){var t,n=this.root,a=Object(v.a)(e);try{for(a.s();!(t=a.n()).done;){var r=t.value;null==n[r]&&(n[r]={}),n=n[r]}}catch(i){a.e(i)}finally{a.f()}n.isWord=!0},kt.prototype.traverse=function(e){var t,n=this.root,a=Object(v.a)(e);try{for(a.s();!(t=a.n()).done;){if(null==(n=n[t.value]))return null}}catch(r){a.e(r)}finally{a.f()}return n},kt.prototype.search=function(e){var t=this.traverse(e);return null!=t&&!0===t.isWord},kt.prototype.startsWith=function(e){return null!=this.traverse(e)};var St=new kt;St.insert("apple"),St.search("apple"),St.search("app"),St.startsWith("app"),St.insert("app"),St.search("app");var wt=function e(){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.children={},this.isEnd=!1},Ot=function e(){Object(o.a)(this,e)},Nt=function(){function e(){Object(o.a)(this,e),this.root=new wt}return Object(s.a)(e,[{key:"addWord",value:function(e){for(var t=this.root,n=0;n<e.length;n++)e[n]in t.children||(t.children[e[n]]=new wt),t=t.children[e[n]];t.isEnd=!0}},{key:"search",value:function(e){var t,n,a=e.length;return t=this.root,n=0,!(!t||n===a&&!t.isEnd)&&(!(n!==a||!t.isEnd)||void e[n])}}]),e}(),xt=new Nt;function qt(){return r.a.createElement("div",{className:"trie"},r.a.createElement("h2",null,"Trees"),r.a.createElement("ul",{id:"trie"},r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"trie-implementation",question:"Trie implementation",solution:"",complexity:"",time:"",space:"",code:yt.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"test-trie",question:"",code:Nt.toString(),secondCode:Ot.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"trie-design",question:"Trie design",solution:"",complexity:"",time:"",space:"",code:kt.toString()}))))}function jt(e){var t,n=e.length;do{t=!1;for(var a=0;a<n-1;a++)if(e[a]>e[a+1]){var r=[e[a+1],e[a]];e[a]=r[0],e[a+1]=r[1],t=!0}}while(t);return e}function zt(e){var t=e.length;if(t<2)return e;var n,a=e[t-1],r=[],i=[],l=Object(v.a)(e.slice(0,t-1));try{for(l.s();!(n=l.n()).done;){var o=n.value;o<a?r.push(o):i.push(o)}}catch(s){l.e(s)}finally{l.f()}return[].concat(Object(I.a)(zt(r)),[a],Object(I.a)(zt(i)))}function Mt(e){for(var t=e.length,n=0;n<t;n++){for(var a=n,r=n+1;r<t;r++)e[r]<e[a]&&(a=r);var i=e[n];e[n]=e[a],e[a]=i}return e}function Ct(e,t){for(var n=[];e.length&&t.length;)e[0]<t[0]?(n.push(e[0]),e.shift()):(n.push(t[0]),t.shift());return n.concat(e,t)}function At(e){if(e.length<=1)return e;var t=Math.floor(e.length/2),n=e.slice(0,t),a=e.slice(t);return Ct(At(n),At(a))}function Bt(e){for(var t=e.length,n=1;n<t;n++){for(var a=e[n],r=n-1;r>=0&&e[r]>a;)e[r+1]=e[r],r-=1;e[r+1]=a}return e}function Tt(e,t,n){var a=n,r=2*n+1,i=r+1;if(r<t&&e[r]>e[a]&&(a=r),i<t&&e[i]>e[a]&&(a=i),a!==n){var l=[e[a],e[n]];e[n]=l[0],e[a]=l[1],Tt(e,t,a)}return e}function Lt(e){for(var t=e.length,n=Math.floor(t/2-1),a=t-1;n>=0;)Tt(e,t,n),n--;for(;a>=0;){var r=[e[a],e[0]];e[0]=r[0],e[a]=r[1],Tt(e,a,0),a--}return e}xt.addWord("bad"),xt.addWord("dad"),console.log("heapSort",Lt([6,5,3,1,8,7,2,4]));function Dt(e){var t,n,a=e.length,r=e.sort((function(e,t){return e-t}));return 0===a?0:(a%2===0?(n=a/2,t=Math.floor((r[n]+r[n-1])/2)):t=r[n=Math.floor(a/2)],t)}console.log("islandPerimeter",function(e){for(var t=e.length,n=e[0].length,a=0,r=0,i=0;i<t;i++)for(var l=0;l<n;l++)1===e[i][l]&&(r+=4),i>0&&l>0&&i<t-1&&l<n-1&&(a+=e[i][l-1]+e[i][l+1]+e[i-1][l]+e[i+1][l]),0===i&&0===l&&(a+=e[i][l+1]+e[i+1][l]),i===t-1&&l===n-1&&(a+=e[i][l-1]+e[i-1][l]);return r-a}([[0,1,0,0],[1,1,1,0],[0,1,0,0],[1,1,0,0]]));var Wt=function(){return r.a.createElement("div",{className:"sorting"},r.a.createElement("h2",null,"Sorting"),r.a.createElement("ul",null,r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"bubble-sort",question:"Bubble sort: bubble up the biggest element to the right most position",solution:"is a method for sorting arrays by comparing each array element to the element behind it",complexity:"Unfortunately bubble sort is pretty slow",time:"\n              (n-1) * (n-1) ... = n2 - 2n + 1 = O(n^2).\n              The worst case situation is reverse ordered array.\n              ",omega:"\n              \u03a9(n) when array is sorted.\n              As the complete array is sorted, your number of swaps will be zero.\n              If you do not swaps just quit.\n            ",space:"O(1)",code:jt.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"selection-sort",question:"Selection sort: move the smallest element to the very left position",solution:"",complexity:"n + (n-1) + (n-2) + ... + 1 = n*(n+1)/2 = (n^2 + n)/2 = O(n^2)",time:"O(n^2) quadratic in all cases, \u03a9(n^2)",space:"",code:Mt.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"insertion-sort",question:"Insertion sort: compare items on its left and shift if needed",solution:"\n              Insertion sort is used when number of elements is small.\n              It can also be useful when input array is almost sorted,\n              only few elements are misplaced in complete big array.\n            ",complexity:"in worst cases number of shifts over that number to the beginning of the array = 1 + 2 + ... + (n-1) = n(n-1)/2 = n^2/2 = n^2",time:"O(n^2)",space:"O(1)",code:Bt.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"merge-sort",question:"Merge sort",solution:"we could magically sort the left half and sort the right half and repeat it again",complexity:"It always give us O(n log n) runtime. There is no case than array looks really funky.",time:"O(n log n)",space:"The downside is merging 2 arrays together requires extra space - O(n) space",code:At.toString(),secondCode:Ct.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"quick-sort",question:"Quick sort: pick a pivot",solution:"first pick a random number - pivot",complexity:"Quick sort\u2019s worst case is O(n^2) (for example, if list was already sorted) but that can be avoided if we pick random pivot point (choose middle one)",time:"O(n log n)",space:"O(log n)",code:zt.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"heap-sort",question:"Heapsort",solution:"",complexity:"",time:"O(nlogn)",space:"O(1)",code:Lt.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"find-median",question:"Find a median",solution:"The median of a list of numbers is essentially it's middle element after sorting. The same number of elements occur after it as before.",time:"",space:"",code:Dt.toString()}))))};function It(e,t){for(var n=e.length,a=0;a<n;a++){return e[a]===t?a:void 0}}function Ft(e,t){for(var n=0,a=(e=e.sort((function(e,t){return e-t}))).length-1;n<=a;){var r=Math.floor(n+(a-n)/2);if(t===e[r])return r;t<e[r]?a=r-1:n=r+1}return-1}function Qt(e,t){var n=arguments.length>2&&void 0!==arguments[2]?arguments[2]:0,a=arguments.length>3&&void 0!==arguments[3]?arguments[3]:e.length-1,r=Math.floor(n+(a-n)/2);switch(!0){case e[r]===t:return r;case a-n===0:return-1;case t>e[r]:return Qt(e,t,r+1,a);case t<e[r]:return Qt(e,t,n,r);default:console.log("Sorry, we are out of expressions")}}function Ht(e){var t=e.length;if(t<=0)return"YES";for(var n=0,a=t-1,r=0;n!==a;)r>=0?(r-=e[a],a--):(r+=e[n],n++);return 0===r?"YES":"NO"}var Rt=function(e){return function(t){for(var n=1,a=t;n<a;){var r=n+(a-n)/2;e(r)?a=r:n=r+1}}};function Pt(){return r.a.createElement("div",{className:"number"},r.a.createElement("h2",null,"Search / Binary search"),r.a.createElement("ul",null,"test",r.a.createElement(g,{id:"test",question:""}),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"is-find-index",question:"Linear search: find an index of element in array",solution:"",complexity:"The worst case performance scenario for a linear search is that it needs to loop through the entire collection.",time:"O(n)",spaceComplexity:"O(1)",code:It.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"binary-search",question:"Binary search with loop while and recursion",solution:"left + right could overflow, correct mid = left + (right - left)/2",complexity:"For iterative and recursive approach: time is O(log n), but for recursive space is O(log n)",time:"O(log n)",space:"O(1)",code:Ft.toString(),secondCode:Qt.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("details",{className:"details",id:"searching-tasks","aria-expanded":"false","aria-labelledby":"label"},r.a.createElement("summary",{role:"button","aria-controls":"content"},"Different tasks related to Binary search"),r.a.createElement(g,{id:"search-balanced-sum",question:"Balanced sum",solution:"challenge is to find an element of the array such that the sum of all elements to the left is equal to the sum of all elements to the right",complexity:"",time:"O(n)",code:Ht.toString()}),r.a.createElement(g,{id:"first-bad-version",question:"First Bad version",solution:"\n                  Suppose you have n versions [1, 2, ..., n] and you want to find out the first bad one,\n                  which causes all the following ones to be bad.\n                ",time:"O(log n)",space:"O(1)",code:Rt.toString()})))))}var Gt=function e(t){return t<=1?"complete":e(t-1)},Jt=function e(t){if(console.log("N",t),!(t<=0))return e(t-1)};function Ut(e){for(var t=0,n=0;n<e.length;n++)t+=e[n];return t}function Yt(e){return e<0?-1:0===e?1:e*Yt(e-1)}!function e(t){0!==t&&e(t-1)}(10);var Zt=function e(t){return 0===t?0:1===t?1:t>1?e(t-1)+e(t-2):void 0};function Vt(e){for(var t=[0,1],n=2;n<=e;n++)t.push(t[n-2]+t[n-1]);return t[e]}function _t(e,t){t=e.length-t;for(var n=0,a=e.length-1;n<a;){var r=$t(e,n,a);if(r<t)n=r+1;else{if(!(r>t))break;a=r-1}}return e[t]}function $t(e,t,n){for(var a=e[n],r=t,i=t;i<n;i++)e[i]<=a&&(Kt(e,r,i),r++);return Kt(e,r,n),r}function Kt(e,t,n){var a=[e[n],e[t]];e[t]=a[0],e[n]=a[1]}function Xt(){return r.a.createElement("div",{className:"number"},r.a.createElement("h2",{id:"recursion"},"Recursion"),r.a.createElement("ul",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"test",question:"",code:_t.toString()}),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"recursion-explanation",question:"Recursion examples",time:"",space:"",code:Ut.toString(),secondCode:Jt.toString(),third:Gt.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"factorial",question:"Factorial using recursion",time:"The time complexity of recursive factorial is O(n)",space:"As there is no extra space taken during the recursive calls, the space complexity is O(n)",code:Yt.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"fibonacci",question:"Fibonacci Number: approach recursion, iterative solution",complexity:"\n              Recursion is the slowest way to solve the Fibonacci Sequence because it takes exponential time.\n              We need space proportionate to N to account for the max size of the stack, in memory.\n              This stack keeps track of the function calls to fib(N).\n              This has the potential to be bad in cases\n              hat there isn't enough physical memory to handle the increasingly growing stack,\n              leading to a StackOverflowError.\n              ",time:"with recursion O(2^n)",space:"with recursion O(N)",code:Zt.toString(),secondCode:Vt.toString()}))))}function en(e){for(var t,n=e.length,a=e.sort((function(e,t){return e-t})),r=Math.abs(a[0]-a[1]),i=2;i<n;i++)(t=Math.abs(a[i]-a[i-1]))<r&&(r=t);return r}function tn(e,t){for(var n=t.slice().sort((function(e,t){return t[0]-e[0]})),a=n.length,r=0,i=e,l=0;l<a;l++){var o=Object(ee.a)(n[l],2),s=o[0];o[1]?(r+=i>0?s:-s,i-=1):r+=s}return r}var nn=function(e){for(var t=0,n=(e=e.sort((function(e,t){return e[0]-t[0]-(e[1]-t[1])}))).length/2,a=0;a<n;a++)t+=e[a][0]+e[a+n][1];return t},an=function(e){for(var t=0,n=(e=e.sort((function(e,t){return Math.abs(t[0]-t[1])-Math.abs(e[0]-e[1])}))).length,a=Math.floor(n/2),r=0,i=0,l=0;l<n;l++){var o=e[l][0],s=e[l][1];o<=s?r<a?(t+=o,r++):(t+=s,i++):i<a?(t+=s,i++):(t+=o,r++)}return t};function rn(){return r.a.createElement("div",{className:"greedy"},r.a.createElement("h2",{id:"greedy"},"Greedy Algorithms"),r.a.createElement(g,{id:"test"}),r.a.createElement("ul",null,r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"greedy-two-city-scheduling",question:"Two city Scheduling",solution:"\n            There are 2N people a company is planning to interview.\n            The cost of flying the i-th person to city A is costs[i][0],\n            and the cost of flying the i-th person to city B is costs[i][1].\n\n            Return the minimum cost to fly every person to a city such\n            that exactly N people arrive in each city.\n            ",time:"O(NlogN) because of sorting of input data",space:"O(1) since it's a constant space solution",code:nn.toString(),secondCode:an.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"greedy-min-absolute-difference",question:"Minimum absolute difference in an array",solution:"We define the absolute difference between two elements a[i] and a[j] (where i!=j), to be the absolute value of a[i] - a[j].",code:en.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"greedy-luck-balance",question:"Luck Balance",code:tn.toString()}))))}var ln=function(e,t){if(e<=0)return 1;var n=new Array(e+1).fill(0);n[0]=1;var a,r=Object(v.a)(t);try{for(r.s();!(a=r.n()).done;)for(var i=a.value,l=1;l<n.length;l++)l>=i&&(n[l]+=n[l-i])}catch(o){r.e(o)}finally{r.f()}return n[e]},on=function(e){var t=new Array(e+1).fill(0);t[0]=t[1]=1;for(var n=2;n<=e;n++)for(var a=1;a<=n;a++)t[n]+=t[a-1]*t[n-a];return t[e]},sn=function(e,t){for(var n=Object(I.a)(Array(e)).map((function(e){return Array(t).fill(0)})),a=0;a<e;a++)n[0][a]=1;for(var r=0;r<t;r++)n[0][r]=1;for(var i=1;i<e;i++)for(var l=1;l<t;l++)n[i][l]=n[i-1][l]+n[i][l-1];return console.log(n),n[e-1][t-1]};console.log("uniquePath",sn(3,2));var un=function(e){for(var t=1/0,n=0,a=0;a<e.length;a++)e[a]<t?t=e[a]:e[a]-t>n&&(n=e[a]-t);return n};console.log("maxProfit",function(e){for(var t=0,n=0;n<e.length-1;n++)for(var a=n+1;a<e.length;a++){var r=e[a]-e[n];r>t&&(t=r)}return t}([7,6,4,3,1]));var cn=function e(t){return t<2?1:e(t-1)+e(t-2)};console.log("climbStairsBruteForce",cn(3));function hn(){return r.a.createElement("div",{className:"dp"},r.a.createElement("h2",{id:"dp"},"Dynamic Programming"),r.a.createElement(g,{id:"test",code:un.toString(),secondCode:cn.toString()}),r.a.createElement("ul",null,r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"db-coin-change-2",question:"Coin change 2: DP and use as outer loop coins array",solution:"\n            Any DP problem should start from explanation of sub problems.\n            The idea is in order to know how many combinations there were for 5,\n            we needed to know how many combinations the previous numbers had.\n            ",time:"O(n*m), where n - coins, m - amount(combinations)",space:"Create an arr of O(amount+1)",code:ln.toString(),secondCode:sn.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"db-num-trees",question:"Unique Binary Search Trees",time:"O(n^2)",space:"O(n)",code:on.toString()}))))}function mn(e){for(var t=arguments.length>1&&void 0!==arguments[1]?arguments[1]:"#",n=t;n.length<e+1;n+=t)console.log("line",n)}var fn=function(){for(var e=1;e<=100;e++){var t="";e%3===0&&(t+="Fizz"),e%5===0&&(t+="Buzz"),console.log(t||e)}};function dn(){for(var e=arguments.length>0&&void 0!==arguments[0]?arguments[0]:8,t="",n=0;n<e;n++){for(var a=0;a<e;a++)t+=(a+n)%2===0?" ":"#";t+="\n"}console.log(t)}function gn(e){return e%2===0||1!==e&&gn(e<0?-e:e-2)}var vn=function(e){for(var t=[],n=e.length-1;n>=0;n--)t.push(e[n]);return t};function pn(e){for(var t=e.length,n=0;n<Math.floor(t/2);n++){var a=e[n];e[n]=e[t-1-n],e[t-1-n]=a}return e}function En(e){var t=[];return function e(n){n.length>0&&(t.push(n.pop()),e(n))}(e),t}function yn(){return r.a.createElement("div",{className:"sorting"},r.a.createElement("h2",null,"Code Sandbox ",r.a.createElement("br",null),r.a.createElement("a",{href:"https://eloquentjavascript.net/"},"Eloquent JavaScript")),r.a.createElement("ul",null,r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"eloquent-looping-triangle",question:"Looping triangle",solution:"Write a loop that makes seven calls to console.log to output the triangle",code:mn.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("details",{className:"details",id:"eloquent-fizz-buzz","aria-expanded":"false","aria-labelledby":"label"},r.a.createElement("summary",{role:"button","aria-controls":"content"},r.a.createElement("span",{className:"question"},"Question:\xa0",r.a.createElement("strong",null,"fizzbuzz"),r.a.createElement("p",null,'Create a for loop that iterates up to 100 while outputting "fizz" at multiples of 3, "buzz" at multiples of 5 and "fizzbuzz" at multiples of 3 and 5'))),r.a.createElement("div",{"aria-hidden":"true"},r.a.createElement("h3",{className:"title"},"Solution:"),r.a.createElement("span",{className:"complexity"},"runtime - O(n)"),r.a.createElement(m.a,{language:"javascript",style:f.a},fn.toString())))),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement("details",{className:"details",id:"eloquent-fizz-buzz","aria-expanded":"false","aria-labelledby":"label"},r.a.createElement("summary",{role:"button","aria-controls":"content"},r.a.createElement("span",{className:"question"},"Question:\xa0",r.a.createElement("strong",null,"Chessboard"),r.a.createElement("p",null,'Write a program that creates a string that represents an 8\xd78 grid, using newline characters to separate lines. At each position of the grid there is either a space or a "#" character. The characters should form a chessboard.'))),r.a.createElement("div",{"aria-hidden":"true"},r.a.createElement("h3",{className:"title"},"Solution:"),r.a.createElement("span",{className:"complexity"},"complexity - n2"),r.a.createElement(m.a,{language:"javascript",style:f.a},dn.toString())))),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"eloquent-is-even",question:"Define whether a positive whole number is even or odd (using recursion): Zero is even, One is odd, for any other number N, its evenness is the same as N - 2.",code:gn.toString()})),r.a.createElement("li",null,r.a.createElement(g,{id:"eloquent-4-reverse-array",question:"Reverse an array",solution:"",code:vn.toString(),secondCode:pn.toString(),thirdSolution:En.toString()}))))}n(220);var bn=function(){return r.a.createElement("div",{className:"main"},r.a.createElement("div",{className:"wrapper"},r.a.createElement(N,null),r.a.createElement(M,null),r.a.createElement(U,null),r.a.createElement(ue,null),r.a.createElement(Ce,null),r.a.createElement(ke,null),r.a.createElement(je,null),r.a.createElement(He,null),r.a.createElement(Ge,null),r.a.createElement(gt,null),r.a.createElement(Et,null),r.a.createElement(qt,null),r.a.createElement(Wt,null),r.a.createElement(Pt,null),r.a.createElement(Xt,null),r.a.createElement(rn,null),r.a.createElement(hn,null),r.a.createElement(yn,null)))},kn=n(9),Sn=n(21),wn=(n(224),function(e){Object(c.a)(n,e);var t=Object(u.a)(n);function n(e){var a;Object(o.a)(this,n),a=t.call(this,e);var r=window.innerWidth;return a.state={sideBarSize:a.getSize(r),sideBarGrowing:!1},a.handleDrag=a.handleDrag.bind(Object(kn.a)(a)),a.onDragFinished=a.onDragFinished.bind(Object(kn.a)(a)),a.onResizerDoubleClick=a.onResizerDoubleClick.bind(Object(kn.a)(a)),a}return Object(s.a)(n,[{key:"getSize",value:function(e){return e>=767?250:67}},{key:"handleDrag",value:function(e){e!==this.state.sideBarSize&&this.setState({sideBarSize:e,sideBarGrowing:this.state.sideBarSize<e})}},{key:"onDragFinished",value:function(){this.setState({sideBarSize:this.state.sideBarGrowing?250:67})}},{key:"onResizerDoubleClick",value:function(e){this.setState({sideBarSize:67===this.state.sideBarSize?250:67})}},{key:"render",value:function(){var e=this.state.sideBarSize,t=this.props.children;return r.a.createElement(Sn.a,{className:e<158.5?"sidebarShortVersion":null,onChange:this.handleDrag,onDragFinished:this.onDragFinished,onResizerDoubleClick:this.onResizerDoubleClick,resizerStyle:{width:"0"},split:"vertical",minSize:67,maxSize:250,size:e},t)}}]),n}(a.Component));n(225),n(226);function On(){var e=location.hash.substring(1);if(e)var t=document.getElementById(e);t&&"details"===t.tagName.toLowerCase()&&(!0===t.open?t.open=!1:t.open=!0)}var Nn=function(e){Object(c.a)(n,e);var t=Object(u.a)(n);function n(){var e;Object(o.a)(this,n);for(var a=arguments.length,r=new Array(a),i=0;i<a;i++)r[i]=arguments[i];return(e=t.call.apply(t,[this].concat(r))).state={},e}return Object(s.a)(n,[{key:"componentDidMount",value:function(){window.addEventListener("hashchange",On)}},{key:"render",value:function(){return r.a.createElement("div",{className:"App"},r.a.createElement(wn,null,r.a.createElement(h,{className:"sidebar"}),r.a.createElement("div",{className:"rightPart"},r.a.createElement("header",{className:"App-header"},"Computer Science Algorithms in JavaScript"),r.a.createElement(bn,null))))}}]),n}(a.Component);Boolean("localhost"===window.location.hostname||"[::1]"===window.location.hostname||window.location.hostname.match(/^127(?:\.(?:25[0-5]|2[0-4][0-9]|[01]?[0-9][0-9]?)){3}$/));l.a.render(r.a.createElement(r.a.StrictMode,null,r.a.createElement(Nn,null)),document.getElementById("root")),"serviceWorker"in navigator&&navigator.serviceWorker.ready.then((function(e){e.unregister()})).catch((function(e){console.error(e.message)}))},27:function(e,t,n){},28:function(e,t,n){}},[[22,1,2]]]);
//# sourceMappingURL=main.2ea459b0.chunk.js.map